Oyshee Saha Roy

1333 South Park Street Halifax, NS, B3J2K9 juni.roy5@gmail.com +19024480058

Highlights of Qualifications

Have used supervised and unsupervised machine learning algorithms on different public data sets to collect meaningful information.

Experience in qualitative and quantitative research using statistical methods in Human Computer Interaction Domain.

Conducted user studies, interviews for designing prototypes and frameworks. Have performed extensive research on human factors and behaviors that influences the designing of any interactive tool. Have performed data analysis and visualization of both qualitative and quantitative data.

Publication

Oyshee Saha Roy and James Blustein, "Protocol to build a Framework for Designing an Interactive Tool for Art Gallery Visitors"," HUMAN'19: 2nd International Workshop on Human Factors in Hypertext Proceedings", 2019, Hof, Germany.

Technical Skills

Languages:

Python, Java, BrightScript, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, shell scripting.

Databases:

MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL

Tools:

Tableau, Mendix, GitHub, Jira, Mantis, Bitbucket, Putty.

IDF:

Anaconda Distributions, Eclipse, Pycharm, Sublime text, Google Colab, Microsoft Visual Studio, Notepad++.

Data Science and Machine Learning:

Algorithms: Apriori, C4.5, Naïve Bayes, Random Forest, K-means.

Python Libraries: Numpy, Pandas, Sci-kit Learn, Matplotlib, Levenshtein.

Education

Master in Computer Science Dalhousie University, Halifax, NS Jan 2018- Aug2019

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science WBUT, Kolkata, India

Aug 2010- June 2014

Work Experience

Student Analyst
Dalhousie Analytics, Halifax, NS

Feb 2019- Aug 2019

- Accessing SciVal, and Scopus APIs and retrieving data.
- Retrieving useful information from JSON and building database.
- Responsible for implementing fuzzy matching on data.
- Responsible for data visualization.

Senior Systems Engineer Infosys Limited, Trivandrum, India Aug 2014 – Dec 2017

- Involved in development of frontend of Rokuapplications.
- Handled database and application servers.
- Experience in working on Agile Methodology.

Thesis and Project Experience

Thesis: Designing a framework to help developers to build interactive devices for art galleries.

Conducted interviews with curators from different art galleries of Nova Scotia, Canada. Qualitative data analysis on the interview data to find out relationships and meaningful information. Researching on different human factors and designing factors that are involved during designing of any tool. Building a framework which will help in future designing of interactive tools for art galleries.

Project: Promoting ACT (Acceptance and Commitment Therapy) through mobile application **Course:** Human Computer Interaction, Fall 2018

Conducted user-studies (online survey, interviews, and user feedback) at different stages of the project. Built low-fidelity and high-fidelity prototype of a mobile application. Conducted A/B testing. Conducted Heuristic evaluations as collected user feedbacks on the prototype.

Project: Heart Disease Prediction using Data Mining Techniques.

Course: Data Mining and Algorithms, Winter 2018

Conducted background research and used public data set for implementation. Used and evaluated the performance of the following algorithms on the data to predict the result: Naïve Bayes Classifier, Random forest algorithm, and J48 algorithm.

Additional Experience

Residence Assistant and Guest Sign-in Staff Dalhousie University, Halifax, NS

Sept 18- Apr 19

- Key responsibilities include interacting with students, hosting residence events and programming, role-modeling, peer counselling and ensuring students' rights to a positive livinglearning environment are respected.
- Responsible for working with Residence Life Staff and Dal Security to promote a safe and inclusive living environment.